hi my name is Jamie Inglis I'm a
business development consultant with
Manulife Inc today I'm going to share
with you three of the most common
reasons financial advisors work with
Manulife Bank well one of the most
common reasons is we are an advisor
based virtual bank and that just simply
means that our products and services
have been designed to support an advisor
and complement their practice being a
virtual bank allows us to create
products that support your client and
save money and more cost-effective for
them in the end you can actually pay off
debt faster and collect interest on a
checking account or we can design
something specific for your clients
financial plan the second point would be
it allows you to see a holistic view of
your clients entire portfolio this
provides you the opportunity to provide
recommendations that are fully
protecting them and preparing them for
their future and in addition in addition
to that it actually builds a fence
around them as well how many times have
you walked into a bank and asked for a
bank draft and we're asked about TFSA
RRSP money this money should be managed
by you and you are the expert to manage
that money so let's keep them out of the
big banks in addition to that how can we
honestly provide recommendation when we
don't know their whole view but we don't
know their debt side how do we know
they're fully protected in most cases
when you provide a recommendation you're
getting additional business and you're
also building that fence around the same
client the third point would be you
actually get money from us so you can
actually earn an income off of this and
in most cases we're doing the work for
you too so for an example let's say you
were to provide two successful referrals
on a monthly basis let's say about
$500,000 over a year's time you could
potentially earn fifteen thousand
dollars in additional revenue so
offering products and services that help
your clients get ahead protect
protecting them from the big banks and
creating an additional revenue or only a
few of the reasons why it's important
that you include banking solutions into
your practice one last thing I'd like to
include is Canadians over $1 sixty-seven
for every dollar
of disposable income that they have that
just means they need your help
and we're here to help you as well with
all of our unique products and solutions
that Manulife Bank we know that you're
not the banking expert so we are here to
help please reach out to your local
business development consultant and we
would be happy to sit down with you and
discuss how easy it is to incorporate
banking solutions into your practice
please visit us on our website Manulife
bank mortgages dot CA thank you so I've
got five kind of key questions that I
hear on a regular basis we'd like to get
your perspective on cool with that all
right
okay so question number one advisors
need to focus on their core product
offerings such as investments or
insurance and not spread themselves too
thin in areas where they're not experts
such as banking would you agree with
that would you disagree with that
statement well how would you respond to
that question sure can everybody hear me
okay I look at my business not as a
Salesman but as an advisor and when it
comes to the area of financial advice I
think it's very important that banking
is a integral part of their financial
planning and I think that not being not
assisting them in this area if you don't
help them this an area people will line
up to help them in that area and they
also line up to steal your business away
for your clients as well
yeah I agree with Dan in that regard I
often talk with my clients about going
to what I call the Google Earth
satellite level view of them before we
get started and taking into account
things that they have that aren't really
going to change and so what I'm trying
to do is provide a holistic view point
for clients and most of them are
resident in Canada they have human
capital in Canada they contribute to the
CPP they have entitlements to OAS they
might have a defined benefit plan they
have a lot of ties to Canada before we
ever get started so
you point that I can bring to the table
is to look more broadly at what they're
doing but in order to see the big
picture on that viewpoint I need to know
what else they have do you ever run into
situations with your clients where they
need to take money from their
investments or they can't pay a premium
on a product like an insurance product
that you're recommending to your client
and you have no idea about where they
have other money because you have no
visibility over their banking and so for
me in my practice I need visibility on
that banking and if I have visibility on
that banking I have solutions that I can
go to to deal with the other tools that
they need I can see that they have money
in the bank for funding a current
contribution to an RSP a TFSA an
insurance policy I know that they have a
buffer for life's events so one key
thing is you know life at some point in
time is going to Zig and their
investment portfolio that you're doing
with them is zagging and it's not a
great time to fund the zig out of the
zag and as a result you need a buffer in
between you need something to go to to
get that money what better thing than
having a huge home equity line of credit
that's available that only has a cost to
access when and if they need it so that
you can have their portfolio fully
invested in things that are more
productive rather than have a bunch of
cash sitting on the sidelines so you've
heard the expression cash is king but
cash isn't paying very well as king so
if you can have access to that liquidity
access to that cash when it's needed
holistically as part of the plan then
you can be much more productive with the
investment side of their portfolio
because you've put in place a tool that
can take care of being that buffer and
that concept is applicable to
all our clients unless they're super
wealthy I remember in 2006 when I was
introduced to the man you won the the
compensation was $400 now that you know
I can't sneeze for $400 when you run an
operation and staff and all of that and
and there was no motivation in that $400
for me whatsoever but we we were doing
some work in in different concepts like
Smith maneuvers and that and they became
that the menu one was a great product
for that and then as I started to work
with a product somewhere along the line
I learned that we got paid 10 bits on
the you know the the balance and you
know you saw my assets under
administration up there 24 million well
I call it the Porsche plan you you know
you can you configure 10 bits on 24
million what that is and how it builds
up over time I remember the day that I
the gals in the office at all your your
man you bank your renewals or this and I
said what and and you know I people
often talk about money but what can i
what kind of car that you want to drive
and it's all in the man you been one
plan I've always felt like if you do the
right thing for your clients the
compensation part is gonna take care of
itself
and I must say I don't pay a lot of
attention to the compensation from it I
feel like I'm motivated if I know I'm
getting something more so for me I feel
like I've got the relationship with a
client
every time I'm meeting with a client I
have an agenda their agenda and my
agenda I review both of those and on my
agenda at some point in time I've got
some other idea some other concept that
I want to be talking with them about
that adds value back to our overall
relationship I need to be constantly
earning the AUM fees or trailers or
what's embedded in the particular
products that I've already put in place
with them every time I have a review
meeting so this is helping me
earn that compensation whether or not
I'm compensated a lot from this but I
think you know a quarter percent on cash
it's not dissimilar to GICs or deferred
annuities or other accumulating products
that's pretty consistent whether it's in
fee-based accounts or otherwise and so
that's the compensation in advantage
accounts and so forth and the
compensation that Dan referred to on
debt under administration is also
incremental but right now you're getting
zero so if I look at it and I wasn't
aware before this meeting exactly what
my assets under administration were but
you know that's paying for one of my
assistants so how many of you could use
more help how many of you could use some
additional administrative services in
your business and still have a marginal
profitability from it so I just hired
our newest assistant this last May after
five years of mentoring her through
University as a summer student but right
now her salaries totally being
compensated by that and it'll be
compensated by that probably for the
next four or five years and if that
keeps growing it might be compensated
for a long time for that particular
individual so that can be good for
business yes sir here this tool is
opening up the flexibilities of other
tools that you have in addition to the
flexibilities in the tool itself so it's
an amazing tool that enables you to get
the most out of other things that the
client has as well that you're providing
and remove some of the uncertainties of
the other tools that you're providing
especially if you're trying to have them
commit to premium streams if they're a
business owner you need flexibility to
adapt to life's uncertainties and this
is it
you